A Guide to the Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, 1991-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Secretary of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia 1991-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/2/1.011
This collection consists of 4,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For ten years from the date of creation, access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or with the specific permission of the Secretary of the Board. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia.
Access restrictions apply to one folder under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by Jeanne F. Bailes, Clerk of the Board of Visitors, Office of the Board of Visitors, The Rotunda, University of Virginia on 2001 August 27.
Biographical/Historical Information
During the time span of these papers, Alexander G. Gilliam, Jr. (1991- ) held the position of Secretary to the Board of Visitors.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of committee files and general records, including correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and related papers.
Contents List
- I: General Files 1968-2001
  - Health Affairs Committee 1999-2001, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Health Affairs Committee--Minutes 1992-2001 (Box 1)
  - Audit Committee--Correspondence 1999-2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Audit Committee--Minutes 2000 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee--Correspondence 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee--Minutes 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee--Minutes 1992-2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Educational Policy Committee--Correspondence 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - Educational Policy Committee--Minutes 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - External Affairs Committee--Correspondence 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - External Affairs Committee--Minutes 2001 (Box 3)
  - External Affairs Committee--Minutes 1992-1996 (Box 3)
  - Executive Summaries 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - UVA Investment Management Company--Minutes 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - UVA Investment Management Company--Minutes 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Investment Subcommittee 1993-1996 (Box 3)
  - Finance Committee--Minutes 1992-2001, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Finance Committee Correspondence--Minutes 1999-2001, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Joint Management Finance and Student Affairs and Athletics 2001 (Box 4)
  - Memoranda to Board Members 1998-1999, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Jones, Mrs. Belva T. Dunn 1991-1994 (Box 5)
  - Harrison, W. Wright 1968-1985 (Box 5)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee-Minutes 1993-2001 (Box 5)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee--Minutes 1992-1996 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee--Correspondence 1999-2001 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee--Minutes 1993-1997 (Box 5)
  - Full Board Meeting 1998-2000 (Box 6)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee--Correspondence 1999-2001 (Box 6)
  - Special Committee on Student BOV Members--Correspondence 1984-1997 (Box 6)
  - University's College at Wise--Correspondence 1999-2001 (Box 6)
  - University's College at Wise--Minutes 1993-2001 (Box 6)
  - Memorandum to the Board 1999, 1-3 of 6 (Box 6)
  - Memorandum to the Board 1999, 4-6 of 6 (Box 7)
  - Minutes--Board Retreat 2000 (Box 7)
  - BOV Memorandum 1990 (Box 7)
  - Preliminary Meeting of the Board 1998-2000 (Box 7)
  - Named Professorships Materials 1998-2000 (Box 7)
  - Human Resources 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Former Members of the Board 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Headline News about UVA 2001 Apr (Box 8)
  - Headline News about UVA 2001 Mar (Box 8)
  - Headline News about UVA 2001 Jan (Box 8)
  - Headline News about UVA 2000 Dec (Box 8)
  - Headline News about UVA 2000 Oct (Box 8)
  - University of Virginia Newsclips 2000 Jul (Box 8)
  - University of Virginia Newsclips 2000 May (Box 8)
  - Headline News about UVA 2000 Oct (Box 8)
  - UVA Investment Management Company--Correspondence 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - University Investment Management Company--Correspondence 1999, 3 folders (Box 9)
- II: Restricted File 1999 (Box 10)